[Music]
[Laughter]
welcome again to the natatorium at the
Nanjing Olympic sports center our first
medals in the diving are ready to be
handed out here as the women prepare to
compete in the final of the 10 metre
platform competition the preliminary
round at 10 metres was certainly
interesting word may quickly have spread
around Nanjing but the local girl looks
set for display you do not want to miss
the shaping look superb that diving puts
the competitors into the harshest of
spotlights disaster literally one slip
away when these rivals will know they
simply have to concentrate on their own
game but let's hope that this medal
that's on offer here will be decided by
outstanding performances oh not on
mistakes their way into the natatorium
here excellent facility part of the big
complex here at the Olympic sports
center already staged six very
entertaining days of swimming
competition and now the attention turns
to five days in all on the diving boards
on the platform and spring wall
China of course the world superpower in
diving certainly they can claim a
historic background as well going right
back a thousand years some of the the
earliest diving they record came from
performers who used to launch themselves
into the water from a swing and then
perform their maneuvers
fast forward thousand years they are
absolutely dominant
well a reminder of the format here for
the final of the women's Timmy to
platform they had a busy eight rounds of
diving in the preliminary competition
the first four rounds involve dives with
a limit on the total degree of
difficulty and those earlier marks are
carried forward into this final now they
have four more dives with no
restrictions to decide who gets up on
that podium at the far end of the ball
China of course overwhelmingly the
dominant country in world diving
especially on their own patch 2008
Beijing Olympic Games seven out of eight
gold medals 2011 in Shanghai at the
world championships ten out of ten gold
medals this is the dive order for this
final eleven competitors four rounds
remember and will champagne the local
heroine here from Nanjing will dive last
loge ie of Malaysia also very impressive
this morning unusualness in junior
competition compared to the seniors that
the marks are carried forward did make
this morning's competition that bit more
competitive rather than just deciding on
the dive order here for these
competitors they've had a long wait if
they traveled with the rest of their
teams here because we've had a week of
competition and finally they got a
chance to get into the pool they will
have been relieved this morning together
to get a feel for this superb facility
check up on a few wishes all the best
and see wala two of them putting on
their iPods or similar to listen to the
music go into their own zone this will
be short and sharp though four rounds
remember eleven competitors the action
will keep on going
they will be very pleased to oily get
this final under way
cat Selina Pfitzner from Belarus will
get us underway in the two and a half
somersault height 2.8 the tariff there
is what a variety the difficulty of the
dives for some of these young divers who
are at different stages of their careers
here we go in the first diving
the 16 year old from Minsk took her time
and her dives in the preliminary
competition one or two rushed this
rather she was quite composed just a
little bit of our attention there as she
went into the water with tight tonic
took position just I had to go wrong
towards the end there before I put those
brakes on for that core strength comes
into play three fives 42 points the
bodies start there so that Karolina
fellows Beltran from Colombia
back the two-and-a-half somersault half
twist these 2.6
recap on the scoring here where's the
crowd responding well to that to divert
from the lung Colombian girl seven
judges top to bottom two marks are
discounted the middle three then are
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
or the tariff to give you a points score
[Music]
that's a tidy enough execution there
fifty-five ninety four the Colombian
police with rocks are added on to the
totals of the first four rounds this
morning young Wally Carlson from Canada
not sixteen till next month but youngest
diver here at the games forward
three-and-a-half Somerset
well she got the spin speed she might
have been looking for but the downside
of that was stopping it we're gonna get
through those rotations as soon as
possible to leave the room to open out
into the perfect entry position you
could see the legs coming over there and
slapping on to the water and 4320
returned she was looking for
from Egypt aha whoo that
forward three and a half somersault
tucked in her opening dive in this final
we had quite an encouraging preliminary
competition remember there from the hole
in door diving pools in Egypt which
really handicaps her training
opportunities especially during the
winter so this environment very much a
new experience for her again that over
rotational entry just leaving a bad
impression there with the judges then
she gets three sixes 4860 it's not all
down to the entry but that is the last
thing the judges see and it can really
influence
raesha Leyland Mahoney is from the
United States
she's from Newton Massachusetts goes to
the half somersault tucked
that's not an encouraging opening guy
from her
give the
the others are finding it tough as this
morning to just hold that entry position
nice and clean all the way through the
water but in general she's where a
decent job of that with 63 points
you need a elevator from Brazil
she won bronze at the qualifying event
in Guadalajara
back in March white showing her best the
preliminary competition though she's got
a back two and a half silver salt 1/2
twist that's worth 3.10
through that twist early on needed to
get into the pike position that little
bit hurried through that and again the
entry not really held as vertically as
she would have hoped
since he's down in a 6.5 that scores 60
2.40
la kelloggi from France she looked very
nice this morning had one lapse but
stylish very elegant or to the laughs an
assault
good applause from the crown but begin
the entry is the weakest part and
junkies will be looking for all the
stages of the dive we lift off the
platform the plank position and then the
finally the entry
oh she's very decent job of that she
could be in there competing for a medal
and she hits her best
loss Nick from Ukraine 18 year old from
Kiev most of these girls also competing
at 3 meters here with an inward two and
a half somersault point
that experience into this competition
having competed at World Championship
level
while being rushed
to find that trigger
this is a long hold
time to go
was it worth the wait turn down a 10 for
composure she was unlucky in Barcelona
in the World Championships
she was 13th in the semi-final missed
out on her place in the final by just
one place
since seven and a half Saturday to
bringing 6440 so that long wait at the
top was pretty well worth it Rafa Rafa
the Olympic silver medalist at 10 meters
the youngest Olympic medalist in Mexican
history at London 2012 and she was just
15 years of age she has got real
pedigree and I don't think we completely
saw that this morning
it would three and a half somersault
tucked this time in the final it's all
for real I think that was a bit more the
sort of show we were looking for in the
preliminary although the first four
rounds didn't count then the divers
could afford to keep a little bit in the
tank good entering position putting it
right the way through the water
just a bit heavy maybe
three sevens steady opening not a
dazzling one but the high tariffs will
give her 6720 no joy from Malaysia
four years ago in Singapore panda layla
from malaysia made her marquis with two
silvers they wouldn't on to become an
Olympic medalist of the real superstar
in Malaysia their guiding is on a big up
all the thriller half somersault they're
very stylish competitor she looked in
the preliminaries on a way back from the
edge of the platform really good tight
tight position reaching out for the
water holding it all the way through
that was nice quick spin speed
wonders she's smiling with 7350 there
the judges were edging towards generous
let's see how they react cue the
applause for new champagne the local
girl from Nanjing who was superb this
morning doesn't give much away for three
and a half somersaults two things to
listen for there just how quiet the
entry was and how quickly applause
responded plenty of heights there
quickly through the rotations
[Applause]
really tight in that Pike position holds
her form
all the way through into the water three
nines slams down her opening score 81
points her four dives in the preliminary
in this section were all 80 plus and
she's at it again she is going to take
some catchy
remember those marks are high because
they had the first four rounds this
morning and it on but whooshing pain is
often storming
[Music]
really announcer they're just asking for
quiet when the divers come to the board
curb their natural enthusiasm that these
games have been enthusiastic but even in
China they don't get the chance to enjoy
this standard of competition that often
anxious coaches around two or four
Katerina
Hitler of Belarus we had before with
three and a half somersault tucked
between point seven
she didn't really get through with four
movements before she hit the water just
coming up rather short and really untidy
entry unfortunately for her
a lot of water big splash
down in the fives 40.5
Kalinina Perez Beltran from Colombia she
didn't compete at the qualifying event
in Guadalajara in Mexico where divers
could grab a place either for themselves
or their country
we're not really able to hit the anchors
smack core strength
we killed these younger divers is not
fully developed yet that's what they
need to just hold that position after
the speed of the somersaulting and you
can see the rotations carrying on there
hence the MSC entry there and he's down
in the 4.5 word from the coach just
explaining what needs to be done
big day for these divers Molly Carlson
I live in Canadian diving from Thunder
Bay in Ontario the denim is very much
concentrated in Quebec and in Montreal
so she has to work somewhat remotely
this of he was in New Delhi for hunt
usual technique of getting into this
Armstead position not to show the judges
she's in full control try and get spring
off the arms and legs
[Applause]
well it's a 3.3 tariffs died so plenty
of ambition from the 15 year old but the
entry was um tidy yet behaving with the
funny strength to get this much lift off
the platform as she really needs good to
see her coming up studying and enjoying
it
three fours oh that's not quite so good
the coach explaining my heart moved out
16 year old was only able to compete in
the Mexico for the qualifier because
she's got two exams out the way then she
has where there is an interesting
chapter
professorship in microbiology instead
forward doubled somersaults here show
the control first that's a good starting
position snap out of the Armstead but
she controlled it well and got herself
into a good position for the entry she's
made up fairly tall ad job of that dive
can be broken down into stages so they
can work on it on the way through and
that is a nice entry position and the
judges think so as well which is even
more important she got to make fives
three eights to count well done
Rachel Aidan Mahoney
got the brothers at three meters in the
qualifier this world junior champion of
the springboard in 2012 competing at
both heights it would three and a half
somersault three point two
and it started well that didn't finish
in quite the same way good position
there through the somersaults but never
got into the right shape to make a clean
entry just lost it there and couldn't
get those legs in a good vertical
position and 34.5 for a modest 4320 put
it behind you move on that's the message
legally de Oliveira
Sheena's afina ranking like the seniors
30th at 10 meters 18 years of age again
with that unusual side starting position
to get into the arm stand for the back
down some salt 1/2 twist extra support
of those wrists nice position long hold
[Applause]
like it's just
slightly untidy finish to the dive just
killing up short run you gotta fight a
bit but
I know because in disaster
- $7 six five four sixty five sixty from
the three point two degree of difficulty
and they tell ye 4-valent
in France showed in the preliminary that
she can produce a very stylish dye she's
got an inward turn of half somersault
which is Dell at two point eight degree
of difficulty she could be pushing for a
little if she could just reproduce some
of the forms from the crew very nice
clean sound on the entry she doesn't to
hang around when she gets into her
position it did seem to rush a couple of
other dives the preliminary but
she's a very attractive figure through
the water
when she's made a good job of that the
judge is giving three-eighths they're
the were the was 18.5 as well and that's
done her no harm
some of the divers looking to put a
towel on the end of the platform then it
give them just a bit more confidence for
the grit before this fall with three and
a half somersault
I also like to tell themselves down and
get dry but often to give themselves a
bit more grip when they get into a pike
position really get good hold on the
thighs and keep the position really
tight
some concentration here
[Applause]
those who seem to get a good bit of
extra height off the platform again we
can compete right across the the range
from one meter just that entry became a
little untidy that looks could have been
a bit tighter together and it would have
been a bit cleaner but it's 5850 from
36.5 for the Ukrainian accountable
Oskaloosa from Mexico
picked silver medalists the synchro
event at this height with Carla Espinoza
back double somersault one and a half
twist three point to the degree of
difficulty control into the gymnastic
position
[Applause]
she's ranked fourteen in the world so
would have come here with real
expectation of being up on that podium
just feel she's not hit her very best so
far
[Music]
and marks confirm it sixty-eight eighty
she's still going to be up there
competing hello je from Malaysia
competed at the recent Commonwealth
Games she was in the 10-meter platform
where she finished eighth and also
synchronized three meter event where she
finished fifth to have great experience
for her only a few weeks ago back
turning off some salt half a twist
[Applause]
good point position that entry either
very nice position they're pulling the
dive all the way through the water the
divers can do a lot of work once they
hit the water to complete the dive for
that still 5980 a decent return from a
2.6 taraf dive now the farce goes around
this arena will shake thing it would
through the half somersault tucked
three point to the degree of difficulty
well she was always going to get a great
response from the crowd that such is the
depth of Chinese diving that Quan shall
we won the qualifying competition at 10
meters won the recent World Cup which is
the biggest event of the year this is
another diver who seems to be able to
churn out the big scores one after the
other so consistent so far look at that
three nines again 8640 top quality top
consistency moon shake peak really is in
a class of her she's already got 61
points plus as a lead but low and a
rough go at Lava putting themselves in
the middle positions after two or four
rounds
no holed up in the tempo of the
competition
our events the charge of feeder the
world governing body are very very
tightly run the girls positioned on
different steps of the 10-meter platform
to be ready to step up there and compete
as soon as possible there's low drop in
the pace Katz theory the good sinner and
further ruse I'm staring back down with
some salt half a twist 2.7 again and she
looks to get the control in that
position
hold
giving extra height you can get for the
push-off will ready give them more
chance of getting through the rotations
and getting into the right entry
position and just see from that front on
angle she was falling away rather at my
tables they're three five five 44 55
this is moving experience for the young
diver that we're not really up there
competing for the medals that is beltro
from Columbia who also a tradition of
producing strong teams for big
international competitions 17-year old
has a back to an a half somersault hiked
2.9
and a very positive start to that dive
you could really see her tense and run
herself into her somersaults you put a
bit untidy again towards the entry point
just as she unwinds and you're going to
see again doesn't really hold the entry
position three sixes 50 to 20 good to
see her enjoy the whole experience so
important please young divers like Molly
Castle at 15 to absorb everything from
the competitive experience the coaches
always spoken to of its so impressed
with the facilities here in Nanjing and
the way they've been received as well
back two and a half solace all hiked 2.9
the crowd reaction said everything about
that execution
you can feel the ground willing every
diver to really try and reflect what
they're capable of but young Molly not
quite managing that into the pike
position just to get the four adjust a
bit more tucked in there and never
really getting out into the correct
entry position to three and a half so
the for two counts 3190 take the
experience out of it my heart glued up
was down in seventh place after there's
two dives he manages to train once or
maybe twice a week hoping that Egyptian
diving can start to push on and that
more they take part of these sort of
competitions the more they'll be able to
push for facilities maha has shown in
some of their dives has got real
potential
2.8 the DD they're very nice
Pike's position sorry they're right on
to her legs
and she's made a pretty tidy job of that
between seven to the seven and a half
but to see if she can get consistency
while across her program racial labeling
Mahoney
[Music]
she's been competing in the World Series
in the Grand Prix events this year on
the feeder calendar usually in the
synchronized events these individual
competitions put so much more pressure
on the delivers Armstead back the double
somersault one and a half twists 3.2
alpha barley higher degree of difficulty
dies
[Applause]
she's been world junior champion x3
meters springboard is the stronger
discipline
isn't enough effort there from the
American though to 7,000 a65 lacy third
is the coach they're having a word with
him
agreed the Oliveira
I think she qualified for this
competitions she said it was the
beginning of a great dream for her for a
former thriller half somersault pike
tier 3.0
spins be there in the rotations
committing totally to the dive just not
quite able again to get into that
entering position
see what the judges think they're pretty
unanimous 36.5 5850
now can la kelloggi produce something
impressive and in herself in medal
contention on stand back double
somersault half a twist tariff is down
to two point seven so she really needs
to make a clean job of this one
now there's no rush she did hurry things
in the preliminary way back to the edge
of that platform
[Applause]
let's feel she could have doubled a
little bit of extra height off the
platform but very hard for these girls
who really get the push cut of the arms
that just might make a bit of a
difference nice entry
to seven point five and a seven and
59:40 just outside the metal positions
affair
got a guy last week
[Music]
verse two the health service out here
a very good you appear in Junior
Championships four foot one liter
just miss Delta LeBrons got silver at
ten meters sir her confidence should be
decent she's in fourth place just trying
to get on to that podium
she tends to take a long time
in the increasingly tension here
this is a love love wait
just be her personal style she does go
she makes a very positive movement at
the top of the herd dive trying to get
extra height with a lot of her to get
into a tight tucked position but again
you can see the entry there was at quite
an angle and there was a big splash and
a low return on the scoreboard with
three Falls
Moscoe Lofa catchy improve on her bronze
position going in to this third of four
dives
and that we've been just a bit more like
it
that's part of the dive Diezel enough
good quick rotations it was just a bit
heavy the backs of her leg and the entry
there just could have got a little bit
tighter maybe no she that's tight enough
but again it was just a untidy entering
with the ankles there the heels slapping
the water
- six and a half's and a seven just feel
there's more to come from her
no Chinese from Malaysia
some Silver's for Malaysia four years
ago from panda Layla who she admits is
her big hero
Malaysia and a very good Commonwealth
Games the men's team were starting to
get up to the same standards that the
women who set
I'm stay back double somersault one and
a half twist well there's an instinctive
neatness to her diving she's very slight
hundred three pounds forty-seven kilos
he was just five foot three
energy always seems to slice our way
into the water
[Music]
steady 10 sevens and a 7.5 68 80 now
[Applause]
the standard setter here in Champaign
[Music]
can she maintain the sky high standards
she's been setting since competition
opened here on stand back double
somersault one a half twist three point
to the tariff for the local style very
quickly and confidently into that
position the one deceives confidence UPS
well if you can produce consistent
diving under standard we've seen from
her so far the seventeen-year-old not
the best entry that we've seen from whoo
so far but it's going to be well enough
to keep her at the top of the pack two
eights and a 7.5 7520 she knows dipped
below 80 points for the first time and
she's not too harsh on herself China
Malaysia Mexico in the medal positions
there could be tight for the silver but
it looks all over at the top of the pack
well he can't sand the back marker at
the moment the youngest diver
very good crowd indeed in here for this
first of five finals in the diving pool
it surprised the Chinese supporters
turnout with the standard they could
expect from their own competitors
the final round of four then here in
this final off a woman's 10 metre
platform competition
Catalina fits not from Belarus ten out
of eleven after three realms
she's only competing on the platform
so she'll want to sign off here with a
nice clean back two and half somersault
with half twist
unfortunately she couldn't do that
competing since she was 9 years of age
always want them to finish off on a high
note and come away with a feeling of
satisfaction for their day's work links
just a bit bent on the night position
she knows he can do better than that
three four fives just 35 points to end
today's belt rim of Columbia
[Music]
big hero is Orlando Duque who is a
famous high diver as in 27 meters need
to think about that height 17-year old
though has enough to deal with on that
10 metre platform in with three and a
half somersault three point to a lot of
the high tariff dives looking for a nice
tidy finish to her program
which is flinch when you know it doesn't
work out for the divers everybody wants
to see a really good standard of
performance if they can rather than
mistakes they're going to affect the
standings but this is very much a
learning experience diving is a tough
sport if have to produce on the day and
they have to learn that no hiding place
48 points she's back to the three meter
event as well Wally Carlson got the
place that had not been won in the
qualifying competition because Canadian
female diving in particular is extremely
strong this will have been a big
experience for her she's back at 3
meters reversed two and a half
somersault to complete her
it was a little bit better again it was
the entry position that gave her
problems
she has ambition out of the pool as well
wants to go on and get a business degree
now in the 5s and the 5 444 84 Molly and
see her occurred later in the games my
heart who dirt is also competing at lo
fights
best Juliet deliver in Egypt for eternal
somersault one twist in sixth place
which would be of encouraging
performance she could just see the
competition through and she has been
pretty consistent which is always
encouraging if you can just roll out
that big mistake dives then you always
got to give yourself a chance of just
reflecting your own particular skill set
a little taller divers here which will
mean that when she gets it right she
will catch an impressive figure
seven and 26.5
what about effort pressure Laden the
holy for her wolf dies
or the eighteen-year-old g2 at five foot
seven is one of the taller divers
there's too many divers started in kim
gnostics so played a bit of ice hockey
helped many divers do that back 1/2
somersault three and a half twists three
point three big twister
she said herself quite a lot to get
through before she hit the water ending
up just trying to hurry herself through
it having a changed position for the
arms to punch a hole for the rest of her
to follow just coming up a little bit
short there
five and two five and a half there again
she's competing on the springboard
ingredie Ora Tara
from Brazil
if their way back from a podium position
but who knows 18 years of age one runs
the qualifying event might reproduce
that threat here well it's really
mattered in the three and a half
somersault
nice sailing injury there
right tucked position just couldn't hold
the entry all the way through there's a
lot of work they can do under the water
pulling the legs through making sure
they complete the dive as impressively
as possible between five and a half six
they're 54:44 Ingrid and they kelloggi
just out of the middle positions two
point eight is the Tara care for the
young French girl back one and a half
two and a half twist two point eight she
needs to actually keep this one as well
as she can and just see what happens
again very quickly into her die
[Applause]
marie chesapeake earth personal style
but we fear that she won't just rush it
a little bit up there the coach said top
six would be a very good return for her
efforts Jenny made her international
debut a full level this year so this is
all priceless experience two sevens and
a 6.5
not quite enough to get into the metal
stakes but progress
there's not like
18 years of age from Kiev at the
national university of physical training
and education forward two and a half
somersault one twist fight
only premium diving is definitely
progressing often competing for the
medals at highest level even so she says
that her big heroes are will be shot in
general in the two outstanding Chinese
divers so she believes in setting her
sights high 360s their 52:24 gana
three to go and we're really now down on
the medal contenders with color will
they be diving for the Olympic synchro
silver medalist from London 2012
Alejandra got off goal offer from Mexico
back to a half Sun salt won a half
twists point three point two is a high B
D
I've actually saved her best points
return until at last and she get in
there and improve on a third position
going into this final round don't think
that the inkling is quite as impressive
though you could see from that angle on
much bigger splash
and down in the six fives 6214 that will
still get her a medal
no Joey
16-year old frog Malaysia just five foot
three
this is to confirm a silver medal for
Malaysia he would threw in a half solar
cell then 3.2
very nice entering really clean sounding
dive don't think that's quite enough of
her to make what you might call a Rick
he slides into the water a very elegant
figure just a little bit angled across
there when we looked at it from that
replay the judges don't see those
replays remember there is a very nice
impression overall about her diving and
she's got two seven-halves
and an eighth and she's got a very big
smile and she has got herself a silver
medal
it has been a one that woman that showed
and here she is washing ping has been
supreme this is one to enjoy can she
really nail it at the final dive of the
competition back to a half somersault
won a half twist three point two well
the gold medalist from start to finish
[Applause]
the local girl comes good big style just
a little bit heavier on the entry but
you've really got to look for the faults
opening out and pulling the dive all the
way through
no wonder she smiles 8.5 80 160 a big
hug and she has kept up those sky-high
Chinese standards China are off and
running with the gold for a whooshing
pain Malaysia get an impressive silver
through low and Orosco Laufer
gets the bronze the Olympic silver
medalist
well who is going to start these Chinese
divers sweeping the board as they did in
Singapore a double-double for them moon
champagne will be back at three meters
and how do you stop such an irresistible
force
well the diving competition is up and
running and if you're not familiar with
the Chinese national anthem you may well
be over the next few days
[Music]
[Applause]
well we've had our first taste of a
diving final here at the natatorium and
certainly the former world junior
champion has put on a great show
it is an endless production line of
outstanding competitors and this crowd
is really looking forward to this
victory ceremony for the women's 10
metre platform event
[Music]
the first victory surelly in the diving
competition at Nanjing 2014 and the
locals have got exactly what they wanted
a local victory the seventeen-year-old
from Nanjing absolutely dominant in her
own backyard she will have this pull
pretty well but she's got a feeling that
wasn't the big difference
[Music]
future looking promising for Mexico with
a bronze individual medal to add to her
Olympic silver synchro medal for
Alejandra
otoscope 17 years of age
[Music]
Mexican diving continues to be strong
Galatian diving continues to go from
strength to strength
Loesch ie following in the pioneering
footsteps of panda lailanie Nam who won
two silvers in Singapore four years ago
and now this 16 year old has another
silver for the Malaysian collection
after a very impressive display
[Music]
world junior champion Chinese national
champion now the Youth Olympic champion
never in doubt from the first time she
stepped up onto that platform an
outstanding performance from an
outstanding prospect more than 75 points
the winning margin and a last she allows
herself a big smile
[Music]
but if you're lucky enough to go to
major international diving competitions
that is the end from you here time after
time after time
what a big crowd has come out to support
the local girl and she rewarded them all
the way with an outstanding performance
wooshing team wins the gold medal by a
street plenty of encouragement though
from the silver and bronze medalists
we'll be seeing more of them as well
four years ago it was Musial who got
double gold in the women's competition
the great chuubo dominated before the
men in Singapore are we going to get
another double double here in Nanjing
one down four to go for China if they're
going to sweep the board here these
supporters have really enjoy